Paul H. Van Tuyl paulvantuyl@gmail.com paulvantuyl.com 928-379-0733 I've been working as a designer full time since 2006. While my education was in graphic design, the majority of my experience has been in digital formats. I fell in love with the web while in school, and come from the era where you had to be able to both design and develop your work.

My professional goal is to use my curiosity, love for design, and craftsmanship to create products, processes, and objects that improve quality of life for human beings.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## **Emotional Design Lead**

Tallwave Scottsdale, AZ Jan. 2015 – Present At Tallwave, I'm designing products so they have an emotional appeal; this is necessary for both product market fit and as a business requirement in today's markets. My responsibilities include User Experience, Interaction, Customer Experience, and User Interface design; leading designers and teams in those efforts; and facilitating design workshops for both business and product design (both with and without customers present). I also direct and create frameworks and methodologies for accomplishing design goals. Occasionally, I get to help out with front-end development .

#### Sr. Product Designer

29th Drive Scottsdale, AZ Sep. 2013 – Dec. 2014 At 29th Drive, we primarily worked as a botique UX Design firm. Team members had to be cross-disciplinary; my responsibilies included UX Design, UI Design, Front End Development, Brand Design, and Email Design. We also worked together as a team to teach businesses with software products how to self-host Design Studios in order to rapidly solve tough problems.

# Creative

iDC Photo Video Prescott, AZ Jan. 2004 – Apr. 2013 While working at iDC Photo Video (now closed), I had tremendous opportunities to work in a range of formats and mediums, and with a tremendous client list. iDC Photo Video also produced a full line of photographic and video production tools and accessories, using a direct-to-customer ecommerce model.

My job responsibilities included website design, development, management, and content creation; Inventory Control System management and integration with website; graphic design, illustration, photo retouching, product photography, video editing, motion graphics, and video EFX. Phone, email, technical, and sales support for products sold through the company website. Worked directly under Bruce Dorn, DGA.



## **Adjunct Faculty Instructor**

Yavapai College Prescott, AZ

Feb. 2009 - Apr. 2009

As an instructor for Magazine Production, I worked with students on the yearly publication of *Threshold Magazine* as a joint project with students from the Graphic Design II class. *Threshold* was a yearly publication from Yavapai College which showcased student writing and artwork.

#### AMAZING CUSTOMERS

Some of the customers I've had the great opportunity to work with throughout my career include ASU, AppointmentPlus, Canon USA, CBANC, Centrieva (Weave), Cybersponse, Full Contour, General Mills, Gibson Dunn, Isagenix, author John Dickerson, Minitab, PayPal, Picmonic, and Western Digital.

## SPEAKING ENGAGEMENTS

Phoenix Design Week, 2015

Phoenix, AZ

Co-presenter for a Startups track workshop, 5 Product & Business Design Secrets for Designers with Great Ideas.

UX Week, 2014

San Francisco, CA

Co-presenter for a UX Week Workshop, Design Studios & Pen Sketching for Makers of Apps & Websites.

## **AWARDS**

**AMA Spectrum Award** 

I led the efforts to create a new logo for AppointmentPlus while working at Tallwave. The logo won an AMA Spectrum Award for Brand Identity in 2016.

#### **EDUCATION**

Associate of Applied Science in Graphic Design

Yavapai College May, 2006 I graduated with honors \ ( ^ O ^ ) / . I decided to begin working immediately for iDC Photo Video full time, rather than further persuing my education. I decided instead to learn as much as I could every day with the information available to me – whether online, from other people, or in books – which is a habit that has stuck with me always.

